<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work stuff on Fernando Paolo</title>
    <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work stuff on Fernando Paolo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fspaolo.net/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Press / media</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</guid>
      <description>On the Larsen C giant iceberg Veja Magazine
Por que é preciso falar sobre o iceberg gigante da Antártida? [Why is it necesary to talk about the gian Antarctic iceberg?]
Appearance in a commercial for Scripps English version
Spanish version
Our Larsen C paper in the news The Washington Post
This ice shelf is nearly the size of Scotland - and it could be at &amp;lsquo;imminent risk&amp;rsquo;
The Guardian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</guid>
      <description>Geophysical Data Analysis Large-scale processing, statistical modeling and time series analysis applied to Earth observations.
I work primarily with observations (i.e. data). I am interested in the large-scale monitoring of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. My past and current work include the mapping and change detection of Earth&amp;rsquo;s topography, bathymetry and gravity field, as observed by radars, lidars, imagery, sonars and gravimeters, among others. The following technologies constitute the core of our tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Journals F. S. Paolo, H. A. Fricker, L. Padman, Developing improved decadal records of Antarctic ice-shelf height change from multiple satellite radar altimeters, Remote Sens. Environ. (2016). web | pdf
P. R. Holland, A. Brisbourne, H. F. J. Corr, D. McGrath, K. Purdon, J. Paden, H. A. Fricker, F. S. Paolo, A. Fleming, Oceanic and atmospheric forcing of Larsen C Ice Shelf thinning, The Cryosphere (2015). web | pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.S. Thesis</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</guid>
      <description>Satellite altimetry and shipborne gravimetry on the integrated representation of the gravity field along the Brazilian coast Abstract. The integration of satellite altimetry data with shipborne gravity surveys has proven essential for the accurate determination of the gravity field over the ocean. This approach has been used extensively due to the high density and availability of data derived from space-borne sensors. Currently, an open problem is the representation of the gravity field elements with high resolution along coastal regions, where the altimeter measurement suffers from degradation due to increased variability in sea-surface height and the presence of the coastline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Dissertation</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</guid>
      <description>Interannual and decadal variations of Antarctic ice shelves using multi-mission satellite radar altimetry, and links with oceanic and atmospheric forcings Abstract. Antarctica&amp;rsquo;s ice shelves, the floating extensions of the ice sheet, exert an important dynamic constraint on the flow of ice from the grounded ice sheet to the ocean, and hence on changes in global sea level. Thinning of an ice shelf reduces its ability to restrain the ice discharge from the grounded ice-sheet interior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>