<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work stuff on Fernando Paolo</title>
    <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work stuff on Fernando Paolo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fspaolo.net/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Press / media</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</guid>
      <description>(Many of the stories include exclusive interviews given)
Outside comment on PNAS sea-level paper Neewsweek
Sea levels are surging at faster and faster rates as Antarctica and Greenland melt, satellite data reveals
Our Nature Geo. ENSO/ice-shelf paper in the news  Video interview for Carbon Brief Video for the press release TV appearance on CBC News  BBC News
El Nino&amp;rsquo;s long reach to Antarctic ice
Carbon Brief
El Niño causes West Antarctica’s ice shelves to gain height yet lose mass</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</guid>
      <description>Geophysical Data Analysis Large-scale processing, statistical modeling and time series analysis applied to Earth observations.
I work primarily with observations (i.e. data). I am interested in the large-scale monitoring of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. My past and current work include the mapping and change detection of Earth&amp;rsquo;s topography, bathymetry and gravity field, as observed by radars, lidars, imagery, sonars and gravimeters, among others. The following technologies constitute the core of our tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Journals S. Adusumilli, H.A. Fricker, M.R. Siegfried, L. Padman, F.S. Paolo, S.R.M. Ligtenberg, Basal melt rates of Antarctic Peninsula ice shelves from satellite radar altimetry, 1994–2016, Geophys. Res. Lett. (accepted)
F.S. Paolo, L. Padman, H.A. Fricker, S. Adusumilli, S. Howard, M.R. Siegfried, Response of Pacific-sector Antarctic ice shelves to the El Niño/Southern Oscillation, Nature Geoscience (in press)
X. Sun, J.B. Abshire., A.A. Borsa, H.A. Fricker., D. Yi, J.P. DiMarzio, F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.S. Thesis</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</guid>
      <description>Satellite altimetry and shipborne gravimetry on the integrated representation of the gravity field along the Brazilian coast Abstract. The integration of satellite altimetry data with shipborne gravity surveys has proven essential for the accurate determination of the gravity field over the ocean. This approach has been used extensively due to the high density and availability of data derived from space-borne sensors. Currently, an open problem is the representation of the gravity field elements with high resolution along coastal regions, where the altimeter measurement suffers from degradation due to increased variability in sea-surface height and the presence of the coastline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Dissertation</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</guid>
      <description>Interannual and decadal variations of Antarctic ice shelves using multi-mission satellite radar altimetry, and links with oceanic and atmospheric forcings Abstract. Antarctica&amp;rsquo;s ice shelves, the floating extensions of the ice sheet, exert an important dynamic constraint on the flow of ice from the grounded ice sheet to the ocean, and hence on changes in global sea level. Thinning of an ice shelf reduces its ability to restrain the ice discharge from the grounded ice-sheet interior.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>