<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Fernando Paolo</title>
    <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Fernando Paolo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Fernando Paolo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fspaolo.net/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Journals Smith B., H.A. Fricker, A.S. Gardner, B. Medley, J. Nilsson, F.S. Paolo, N. Holschuh, S. Adusumilli, K. Brunt, B. Csatho, K. Harbeck, T. Markus, T. Neumann, M.R. Siegfried, H.J. Zwally, Pervasive ice sheet mass loss reflects competing ocean and atmosphere processes, Science (2020)
Gudmundsson G.H., F.S. Paolo, S. Adusumilli, H.A. Fricker, Instantaneous Antarctic ice sheet mass loss driven by thinning ice shelves, Geophysical Research Letters (2019)
Adusumilli S., H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Thesis</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</guid>
      <description>Interannual and decadal variations of Antarctic ice shelves using multi-mission satellite radar altimetry, and links with oceanic and atmospheric forcings Antarctica&amp;rsquo;s ice shelves, the floating extensions of the ice sheet, exert an important dynamic constraint on the flow of ice from the grounded ice sheet to the ocean, and hence on changes in global sea level. Thinning of an ice shelf reduces its ability to restrain the ice discharge from the grounded ice-sheet interior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.S. Thesis</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</guid>
      <description>Satellite altimetry and shipborne gravimetry on the integrated representation of the gravity field along the Brazilian coast The integration of satellite altimetry data with shipborne gravity surveys has proven essential for the accurate determination of the gravity field over the ocean. This approach has been used extensively due to the high density and availability of data derived from space-borne sensors. Currently, an open problem is the representation of the gravity field elements with high resolution along coastal regions, where the altimeter measurement suffers from degradation due to increased variability in sea-surface height and the presence of the coastline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</guid>
      <description>Many of the stories include exclusive interviews given.
Our paper in Science Media coverage of our Science paper on pervasive ice sheet loss from NASA&amp;rsquo;s satellite laser mission
 “With the unprecedented accuracy and precision of this novel measurement system, we are now able to detect the small signals far into the ice sheet interior, as well as map out the changes over narrow glaciers on high-slope terrain around the ice sheets,” said study coauthor Fernando S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</guid>
      <description>I work primarily with observations (i.e. data). I am interested in the large-scale monitoring of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface and climate. My past and current work include mapping out from space the Earth&amp;rsquo;s topography, bathymetry and gravity field, using radars, lidars, sonars and gravimeters, among others. I develop algorithms for remote-sensing applications and use computer clusters to process large-scale satellite measurements. I am a strong advocate of open source and open data!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>