<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection - Fernando Paolo</title>
    <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Fernando Paolo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Fernando Paolo</copyright>
    
        <atom:link href="http://fspaolo.net/think/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The regrets of the dying</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/regrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/regrets/</guid>
      <description>Bronnie Ware is an Australian nurse who spent several years working in palliative care, caring for patients in the last 12 weeks of their lives. She recorded their dying epiphanies in a blog. &amp;ldquo;When questioned about any regrets they had or anything they would do differently,&amp;rdquo; she says, &amp;ldquo;common themes surfaced again and again.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ldquo;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>The search for reason</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/reason/</guid>
      <description>Giordano Bruno Remains therefore committed to a fierce struggle until the end against ignorance, prejudice, intolerance and dogma.
 It should never stand as argument the authority of any man, regardless of how excellent and illustrious he is&amp;hellip; it is grossly unfair to fold one&amp;rsquo;s own feeling to a submissive reverence toward another; it is worthy of mercenaries or slaves and contrary to the dignity of human freedom to suppress oneself and to be submissive; it is supreme stupidity to believe by inveterate custom; it is an irrational thing to conform with an opinion because of the number of those who have it&amp;hellip; it has to be sought, instead, always a reason, true and necessary&amp;hellip; and listen to the voice of nature.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>The uncopyright mindset</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/uncopyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/uncopyright/</guid>
      <description>As some might know, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of copyright. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve uncopyrighted this blog and my other blog, Zen Habits.
&amp;nbsp;
And while uncopyright and minimalism might seem at first glance to be unrelated, I believe they both stem from the same mindset.
&amp;nbsp;
Here&amp;rsquo;s how.
&amp;nbsp;
Copyright stems from a protective mindset, one that believes the creator owns his work, and must protect that ownership in order to profit from said work.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>The zen of Python</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/python/</guid>
      <description>Long time Pythoneer Tim Peters succinctly channels the BDFL&amp;rsquo;s guiding principles for Python&amp;rsquo;s design into 20 aphorisms, only 19 of which have been written down.
 Beautiful is better than ugly. Explicit is better than implicit. Simple is better than complex. Complex is better than complicated. Flat is better than nested. Sparse is better than dense. Readability counts. Special cases aren&amp;rsquo;t special enough to break the rules. Although practicality beats purity.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>What is happines?</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/happiness/</guid>
      <description>There is no path to happiness: happiness is the path
&amp;mdash; Gautama Buddha, around 500 BC
&amp;nbsp;
Of all forms of caution, caution in love is perhaps the most fatal to true happiness
&amp;mdash; Bertrand Russell, early 1800s
&amp;nbsp;
Happiness is the feeling that power increases &amp;ndash; that resistance is being overcome
&amp;mdash; Friedrich Nietzsche, late-19th century
&amp;nbsp;
The secret of happiness, you see, is not found in seeking more, but in developing the capacity to enjoy less</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Who cares about them</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/persecution/</guid>
      <description>First they came for the Communists, and I did not speak out—
&amp;nbsp;
Because I was not a Communist.
&amp;nbsp;
Then they came for the Trade Unionists, and I did not speak out—
&amp;nbsp;
Because I was not a Trade Unionist.
&amp;nbsp;
Then they came for the Jews, and I did not speak out—
&amp;nbsp;
Because I was not a Jew.
&amp;nbsp;
Then they came for me—
&amp;nbsp;
and there was no one left to speak for me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>