<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinks on VEX Bootstrap 4 Product Landing Page</title>
    <link>https://www.example.com/think/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinks on VEX Bootstrap 4 Product Landing Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.example.com/think/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism and life time</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>I have thought a lot about that. I spent over ten years in solitary, in a hole. Plenty of time to think&amp;hellip; I spent seven years without one book! That left me time to think. And this is what I discovered: Either you&amp;rsquo;re happy with very little, free of all that extra luggage, because you have happiness inside, or you don&amp;rsquo;t get anywhere! I am not advocating poverty. I am advocating sobriety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making work better and more efficient</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Large-format meetings waste people&amp;rsquo;s time.
 Excessive meetings are the blight of big companies and almost always get worse over time. Please get [rid] of all large meetings, unless you&amp;rsquo;re certain they are providing value to the whole audience, in which case keep them very short.
 Meetings should be infrequent unless a matter is urgent.
 Also get rid of frequent meetings, unless you are dealing with an extremely urgent matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message to future generations</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/generations/</guid>
      <description>— What would you think it&amp;rsquo;s worth telling future generations about the life you&amp;rsquo;ve lived and the lessons you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from it?
 I should like to say two things, one intellectual and one moral. The intellectual thing I should want to say is this: When you are studying any matter, or considering any philosophy, ask yourself only what are the facts and what is the truth that the facts bear out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven signs of non-competitive states</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/states/</guid>
      <description>Traditional indicators of noncompetitive performance still apply: corruption (the most seductive activity humans can consummate while clothed); the absence of sound, equitably enforced laws; civil strife; or government attempts to overmanage a national economy. As change has internationalized and accelerated, however, new predictive tools have emerged. They are as simple as they are fundamental, and they are rooted in culture. The greater the degree to which a state &amp;mdash; or an entire civilization &amp;mdash; succumbs to these &amp;ldquo;seven deadly sins&amp;rdquo; of collective behavior, the more likely that entity is to fail to progress or even to maintain its position in the struggle for a share of the world&amp;rsquo;s wealth and power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internationalization of Amazonia</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/amazonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/amazonia/</guid>
      <description>During a recent discussion, in the United States, someone asked my opinion regarding the internationalization of the Amazon Region. The youngster asserted that he expected a response of a humanist and not of a Brazilian.
This was the first time anyone had established the humanist viewpoint as the starting point for my response. In fact, as a Brazilian I would have responded simply against internationalization of the Amazon Region. Even if our governments have not given the attention that this treasure deserves, it is ours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of science denial</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/denial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/denial/</guid>
      <description>[&amp;hellip;] in this, the 21st century, when it comes time to make decisions about science, it seems to me people have lost the ability to judge what is true and what is not. What is reliable and what is not reliable. What you should believe, and what should you not believe.
And when you have people who don’t know much about science standing in denial of it and rising to power, that is a recipe for the complete dismantling of our informed democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The essence of simplicity</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/simplicity/</guid>
      <description>Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing more to add, but when there is nothing left to take away.
&amp;mdash; Antoine de saint-exupéry
Plurality should not be assumed without necessity.
&amp;mdash; William of Ockham (Ockham’s Razor)
Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.
&amp;mdash; Albert Einstein
The ability to simplify means to eliminate the unnecessary so that the necessary may speak.
&amp;mdash; Hans Hofmann</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The investment of societies</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/societies/</guid>
      <description>No society wants you to become wise: it is against the investment of all societies. If people are wise, they cannot be exploited. If they are intelligent, they cannot be subjugated, they cannot be forced into a mechanical life, to live like robots. They will assert themselves &amp;mdash; they will assert their individuality. They will have the fragrance of rebellion around them; they will want to live in freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The purpose of religion</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/religion/</guid>
      <description>I cannot understand why we idle discussing religion. If we are honest - and scientists have to be - we must admit that religion is a jumble of false assertions, with no basis in reality. The very idea of God is a product of the human imagination. It is quite understandable why primitive people, who were so much more exposed to the overpowering forces of nature than we are today, should have personified these forces in fear and trembling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The regrets of the dying</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/regrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/regrets/</guid>
      <description>Bronnie Ware is an Australian nurse who spent several years working in palliative care, caring for patients in the last 12 weeks of their lives. She recorded their dying epiphanies in a blog. &amp;ldquo;When questioned about any regrets they had or anything they would do differently,&amp;rdquo; she says, &amp;ldquo;common themes surfaced again and again.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ldquo;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The search for reason</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/reason/</guid>
      <description>[Giordano Bruno] Remains therefore committed to a fierce struggle until the end against ignorance, prejudice, intolerance and dogma.
 It should never stand as argument the authority of any man, regardless of how excellent and illustrious he is&amp;hellip; it is grossly unfair to fold one&amp;rsquo;s own feeling to a submissive reverence toward another; it is worthy of mercenaries or slaves and contrary to the dignity of human freedom to suppress oneself and to be submissive; it is supreme stupidity to believe by inveterate custom; it is an irrational thing to conform with an opinion because of the number of those who have it&amp;hellip; it has to be sought, instead, always a reason, true and necessary&amp;hellip; and listen to the voice of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The uncopyright mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/uncopyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/uncopyright/</guid>
      <description>As some might know, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of copyright. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve uncopyrighted this blog and my other blog, Zen Habits.
And while uncopyright and minimalism might seem at first glance to be unrelated, I believe they both stem from the same mindset.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how.
Copyright stems from a protective mindset, one that believes the creator owns his work, and must protect that ownership in order to profit from said work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The zen of Python</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/python/</guid>
      <description>Long time Pythoneer Tim Peters succinctly channels the BDFL&amp;rsquo;s guiding principles for Python&amp;rsquo;s design into 20 aphorisms, only 19 of which have been written down.
 Beautiful is better than ugly. Explicit is better than implicit. Simple is better than complex. Complex is better than complicated. Flat is better than nested. Sparse is better than dense. Readability counts. Special cases aren&amp;rsquo;t special enough to break the rules. Although practicality beats purity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who cares about them</title>
      <link>https://www.example.com/think/persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.example.com/think/persecution/</guid>
      <description>First they came for the Communists, and I did not speak out—
Because I was not a Communist.
Then they came for the Trade Unionists, and I did not speak out—
Because I was not a Trade Unionist.
Then they came for the Jews, and I did not speak out—
Because I was not a Jew.
Then they came for me—
and there was no one left to speak for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>