<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@fspaolo - Fernando Paolo</title>
    <link>http://fspaolo.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in @fspaolo on Fernando Paolo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Fernando Paolo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://fspaolo.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Press</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/press/</guid>
      <description>Media coverage of my work and interviews given to the press</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/research/</guid>
      <description>My research work and the projects I collaborate(d) with</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed papers and general-audience articles</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>M.S. Thesis</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/ms/</guid>
      <description>Satellite altimetry and shipborne gravimetry on the integrated representation of the gravity field along the Brazilian coast</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ph.D. Dissertation</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/work/phd/</guid>
      <description>Interannual and decadal variations of Antarctic ice shelves using multi-mission satellite radar altimetry, and links with oceanic and atmospheric forcings</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Consumerism and life time</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>I have thought a lot about that. I spent over ten years in solitary, in a hole. Plenty of time to think&amp;hellip; I spent seven years without one book! That left me time to think. And this is what I discovered: Either you&amp;rsquo;re happy with very little, free of all that extra luggage, because you have happiness inside, or you don&amp;rsquo;t get anywhere! I am not advocating poverty. I am advocating sobriety.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>I set my hearth on learning</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/learning/</guid>
      <description>When I was fifteen I set my heart on learning.
&amp;nbsp;
At thirty I took my stand.
&amp;nbsp;
At forty I was without confusion.
&amp;nbsp;
At fifty I knew the command of Tian.
&amp;nbsp;
At sixty I heard it with a compliant ear.
&amp;nbsp;
At seventy I follow the desires of my heart and do not overstep the bounds.
&amp;nbsp;
 (alternative translation)
 At fifteen, I set my heart on learning.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Making work better and more efficient</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Large-format meetings waste people&amp;rsquo;s time.
 Excessive meetings are the blight of big companies and almost always get worse over time. Please get [rid] of all large meetings, unless you&amp;rsquo;re certain they are providing value to the whole audience, in which case keep them very short.
 Meetings should be infrequent unless a matter is urgent.
 Also get rid of frequent meetings, unless you are dealing with an extremely urgent matter.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Message to future generations</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/generations/</guid>
      <description>— What would you think it&amp;rsquo;s worth telling future generations about the life you&amp;rsquo;ve lived and the lessons you&amp;rsquo;ve learned from it?
 I should like to say two things, one intellectual and one moral. The intellectual thing I should want to say is this: When you are studying any matter, or considering any philosophy, ask yourself only what are the facts and what is the truth that the facts bear out.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Seven signs of non-competitive states</title>
      <link>http://fspaolo.net/think/states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fspaolo.net/think/states/</guid>
      <description>Traditional indicators of noncompetitive performance still apply: corruption (the most seductive activity humans can consummate while clothed); the absence of sound, equitably enforced laws; civil strife; or government attempts to overmanage a national economy. As change has internationalized and accelerated, however, new predictive tools have emerged. They are as simple as they are fundamental, and they are rooted in culture. The greater the degree to which a state &amp;mdash; or an entire civilization &amp;mdash; succumbs to these &amp;ldquo;seven deadly sins&amp;rdquo; of collective behavior, the more likely that entity is to fail to progress or even to maintain its position in the struggle for a share of the world&amp;rsquo;s wealth and power.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>